String Index	Text
Lore1	A Tome
greatconflict2	45\nThe Great Conflict\n\nTake heed and bear witness to the truths \nthat lie herein, for they are the last legacy \nof the Horadrim. There is a war that rages \non even now, beyond the fields that we \nknow - between the utopian kingdoms of \nthe High Heavens and the chaotic pits of \nthe Burning Hells. This war is known as \nthe Great Conflict, and it has raged and \nburned longer than any of the stars in the \nsky. Neither side ever gains sway for long \nas the forces of Light and Darkness \nconstantly vie for control over all creation.\n
greatconflict	30\nThe Great Conflict\n\nSince the beginning, the forces of light \nand darkness have engaged in an \neternal war: The Great Conflict, whose \nvictor will rise from the apocalyptic \nashes to hold sway over all creation. \nTo this end, the angels of the high \nheavens adhere to strict militaristic \ndisciplines. Seraphim warriors strike at \nthe enemies of light with swords \nimbued with righteous wrath and \njustice. The angels believe that only \nabsolute discipline can properly \nrestore order to the myriad realms, \nwhile the demonic denizens of the \nburning hells hold that absolute chaos \nis the true nature of all things.\n\nThe battles of the Great Conflict rage \nacross both time and space often \ninfringing upon the very fabric of reality \nitself. From the Crystal Arch at the very \nheart of the high heavens to the \narcane Hellforge of the underworld, \nthe warriors of these eternal realms \njourney to wherever their timeless \nconflict carries them. The legendary \ndeeds of the heroes of the realms \nbeyond elicit both veneration and \ninsight.\n\nThe greatest of these heroes was \nIzual, lieutenant to the arch-angel \nTyrael and bearer of the angelic \nruneblade Azurewrath. He once led a \nfierce attack upon the Hellforge as \nthe creation of the dark demonblade \nShadowfang was nearing completion. \nHis quest was to destroy both wielder \nand weapon - a charge that he was \ndestined never to complete. Izual was \novercome by the legions of chaos and,\ntragically, was lost to the Darkness. \nHis fate stands as testament to the \nfact that Angels and Demons alike \nshall fearlessly enter into any domain - \nso long as their hated enemies dwell \nwithin.\n\nAlthough the Great Conflict burned \nhotter and longer than any of the stars \nin the sky, neither side could gain \ndominion over the other for long. Both \nfactions sought some way to turn the \ntides of the war to their favor. With the \nascension of man and his mortal realm, \nthe Great Conflict ground to a \nmysterious halt. Both armies paused in \na breathless stalemate, waiting to see \nto whose side man would eventually \nturn.\n\nMortals had the unique ability to \nchoose between darkness and light,\nand it was held that this would be the \ndeciding factor in the outcome of the \nGreat Conflict. Thus, the agents of the \nnether-realms descended to the mortal \nrealm to vie for the favor of man...\n
blackking	30\nThe Fall of the Black King\n\nThe war against the zealous armies of \nWestmarch ended with a horrible \nslaughter. With the army of Khanduras \nripped to shreds by the superior \nnumbers and defensive positions of \nWestmarch, Lachdanan quickly \ngathered together those who were not\ncaptured or killed and ordered a \nretreat back to the safety of \nKhanduras. They returned to find the \ntown of Tristram in shambles.\nKing Leoric, deep within the thrones \nof madness, went into a rage when he \nlearned that his son was missing. After \nscouring the village with the few \nguards that remained within at the \nmonastery, Leoric had decided that \nthe townsfolk had abducted his son \nand hidden him somewhere. Although\nthe townsfolk denied any knowledge \nof Prince Albrecht's whereabouts, \nLeoric insisted that they had crafted a \nconspiracy against him, and that they \nwould pay the price for such treachery.\n\nThe mysterious disappearance of the \narch-bishop Lazarus left no one in \nTristram with whom the king would \ntake council. Overcome by grief and \ndementia, Leoric had many of the \ntownsfolk executed for the crime of \nhigh treason.\n\nAs Lachdanan and his fellow survivors \nreturned to confront their king, Leoric \nsent his few remaining guards against \nthem. Believing that Lachdanan was \nsomehow part of the townsfolk's \nconspiracy, Leoric decreed that he \nand his party were to die. Lachdanan, \nfinally realizing that Leoric was beyond \nsalvation, ordered his men to defend \nthemselves. The ensuing battle \ncarried them down into the very halls \nof the darkened monastery, bringing a \nfinal desecration to the once holy \nsanctum of the Horadrim. Lachdanan \nwon a bittersweet victory as his men \nwere forced to kill all of Leoric's \ndeceived protectors. They cornered \nthe ravenous king within his own \nsanctuary and begged him to explain \nthe atrocities he had committed. \nLeoric only spat at them and cursed \nthem for traitors against both his crown \nand the light.\n\nLachdanan walked slowly towards his \nking and sorrowfully drew his sword. \nFull of grief and rage, all honor having \nbeen cast to the winds, Lachdanan \nran his blade through Leoric's \nshriveled, blackened heart. The once \nnoble king screamed an unearthly \ndeath-cry, and as his madness finally \novertook him, he brought down a \ncurse upon those who had so \nbetrayed him. Calling upon the forces \nof darkness that he had spent his \nentire life combating, Leoric \ncondemned Lachdanan and the \nothers to eternal damnation. In that \nlast, fleeting moment within the heart \nof the monastery, all that was ever \nvirtuous or honorable about the \nstewards of Khanduras was shattered\nforever.\n
sinwar	30\nThe Sin War\n\nThe coming of the Great Conflict to the \nmortal realm is known as the Sin War. \nAngels and demons, disguising \nthemselves while traveling amongst \nmen, attempted to secretly lure mortals \nto their respective causes. Over time, \nthe forces of darkness discovered that \nmortals responded much more to brute \nforce than to subtle coercion, and so \nbegan to terrorize man into submission. \nThe angels fought to defend humanity \nagainst this demonic oppression, but \nall too often their austere methods and \nsevere punishments succeeded only in \nalienating those whom they sought to \nprotect.\n\nThe violent battles of the Sin War \noccurred often, but they were seldom \nwitnessed by the prying eyes of man. \nOnly a few "enlightened" souls were \naware of the supernatural beings that \nwalked amongst the huddled masses \nof humanity. Powerful mortals arose \nand accepted the challenge of the Sin \nWar, allying themselves with both \nsides in the Great Conflict. The \nlegendary deeds of these great mortal \nwarriors served to earn both the \nrespect and hatred of the netherworlds.\nAlthough lesser demons kneeled\nbefore those possessing power and \nstrength, they also cursed  the very\nexistence of mortal man. Many  of \nthese fiends believed that the \ndeadlock brought about by the \nemergence of Man was a perverse \noffense to their "higher" role in the \ngreat scheme of things.\n\nThis jealousy of man led to harsh, \natrocious acts of violence by the \ndemons against the mortal realm. \nSome men learned of this deep hatred\nand used it against the denizens of the \nunderworld. One such mortal, Horazon \nthe Summoner, delighted in \nsummoning demons and then breaking\nthem to his will. Horazon, along with \nhis brother Bartuc, were members\nof the Eastern mage clan known as \nthe Vizjerei. This mystic clan studied\nthe ways of demons and had \ncatalogued their lore for generations. \nEmpowered by this knowledge, \nHorazon was able to take the work of \nthe Vizjerei and pervert it for his \ndemented purposes. The denizens of \nhell sought revenge against this bold \nmortal, but Horazon managed to keep \nhimself well protected within his \narcane sanctuary.\n\nBartuc, the brother of Horazon, was \neventually  lured to the side of \ndarkness. He was granted exceptional \nstrength and longevity, and fought\nalongside the legions of hell against \nthe cursed Vizjerei, and eventually his \nown brother during the Sin War. \nAlthough Bartuc was renowned \namongst the warriors of many realms, \nhis dominance in battle came with a \nterrible price. An insatiable lust for \nmortal blood pervaded his every \nthought and deed. Bartuc soon \nbecame as fond of bathing in the \nblood of his enemies as he did of \nshedding it, and in time he came to be \nknown only as the Warlord of Blood.\n
darkexile	30\nThe Dark Exile\n\n"Seven is the number of the powers of \nHell, and Seven is the number of the \nGreat Evils."\n\n        Duriel, the Lord of Pain\n        Andariel, the Maiden of Anguish\n        Belial, the Lord of Lies\n        Azmodan, the Lord of Sin\n\nThese are the true names of the \nlesser of the great evils. For ages \nuncounted each have ruled over their \nown domains within the burning hells, \nseeking  absolute dominion  over their\ninfernal brethren. As the lesser four \ncontinuously vied for the control of \nthose forces that dwelled within their \nrealms, the greater three held \nabsolute power over the whole of Hell. \nThe lesser four used dark and evil \nmeasures in their quest for power, and \nherein begins the legend of the Exile.\n\n        Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred\n        Baal, the Lord of Destruction\n        Diablo, the Lord of Terror\n\nThese are the prime evils of hell that \nwielded their power as a dark, \nsovereign triumvirate. The three \nbrothers ruled over the lesser four by \nbrutal force and malicious cunning. \nBeing the eldest and strongest of the \nevils, the three brothers were \nresponsible for countless victories \nagainst the armies of the light. \nAlthough they never held sway over \nthe high heavens for long, the three \nwere justly feared by enemies and \nsubjects alike.\n\nWith the ascension of man and the \nsubsequent standstill of the Great \nConflict, the three brothers began to \ndevote their energies to the \nperversion of mortal souls. The three \nrealized that man was the key to \nvictory in the war against Heaven, \nand thus altered their rigid agendum\nthat they had propagated since the \nbeginning. This change caused many\nof the lesser evils to question the \nauthority of the three, and so brought\nabout a great rift between the prime \nevils and their servitors. In their \nignorance, the lesser evils began to \nbelieve that the three were afraid to \ncontinue the war with heaven. \nFrustrated by the cessation of the war,\nAzmodan and Belial saw the situation \nas their chance to overthrow the \nprime evils and take control of hell for \nthemselves. The two demon lords \nmade a pact with their minor brethren, \nassuring them that the wretched \nplague of humanity would not deter \nthe ultimate victory of the Sons of Hell. \nAzmodan and Belial devised a plan to \nend the stalemate, achieve victory in \nthe Sin War and ultimately ride the \nbloody crest of the Great Conflict \nstraight into the very arms of \nArmageddon. Thus, a great revolution\nwas set into motion as all of hell went \nto war against the three brothers...\n
bingingofthe3	30\nThe Binding of the Three\n\nIn the ancient days, before the rise of \nthe western empires, the dark and \nterrible entities known as the three \nevils were exiled to the world of man. \nThese eternal entities wandered \nthroughout the waking world and fed \nupon the lusts of men, leaving chaos \nand attrition in their wake. The evils \nturned father against son and \nprompted many great nation into \nbrutal and petty wars. Their exile from \nhell left them with an insatiable hunger \nto bring suffering and pain to all those \nwho would not kneel before them, \nand so the three brothers ravaged the \nlands of the far east for countless \ncenturies.\n\nEventually, a secretive order of mortal \nmagi was gathered together by the \nenigmatic arch-angel Tyrael. These \nsorcerers were to hunt the three evils \nand put an end to their vicious \nrampage. The order, known as the\nHoradrim, consisted of wizards from \nthe diverse and numerous mage-clans\nof the east. Employing disparate \nmagical practices and disciplines, this\nunlikely brotherhood succeeded in \ncapturing two of the brothers within\npowerful artifacts called Soulstones. \nMephisto and Baal, trapped within\nthe swirling, spiritual constraints of the \nSoulstones, were then buried beneath \nthe dunes of the desolate eastern \nsands.\n\nThe powers of hatred and wanton \ndestruction seemed to diminish in the \neast as a nervous peace began to \nsettle over the land. Yet, for many \ndecades the Horadrim continued their \ngrim search for the third brother, \nDiablo. They knew that if the Lord of \nTerror was left untamed, there could\nnever be any lasting peace within the \nrealm of humanity.\n\nThe Horadrim followed in the wake of \nterror and anarchy that spread\nthroughout the western lands. After a \ngreat battle which claimed the lives\nof many brave souls, the Lord of \nTerror was captured and imprisoned \nwithin the last of the Soulstones by a \ngroup of Horadrim monks led by the \ninitiate Jered Cain. These monks \ncarried the cursed stone to the land \nof Khanduras and buried it within a \nsecluded cave near the river \nTalsande. Above this cave the \nHoradrim constructed a great \nmonastery from which they could\ncontinue to safeguard the Soulstone. \nAs ages passed, the Horadrim \nconstructed a network of catacombs \nbeneath the monastery to house the \nearthly remains of the martyrs of their \norder.\n\nGenerations passed in Khanduras, \nand the numbers of the Horadrim\nslowly dwindled. With no quests left \nto undertake, and too few sons to\nsustain their guardianship, the once \npowerful order faded into obscurity.\nEventually, the great monastery that \nthey had built fell to ruins as well.\nAlthough villages grew and thrived \naround the shell of the old monastery,\nno one knew of the dark, secret \npassageways that stretched into the \ncold earth beneath it. None could \nhave dreamed of the burning red \ngem that pulsed within the labyrinth's \nheart...\n
landsofkhanduras	30\nThe Lands of Khanduras\n\nYears after the last of the Horadrim \nhad died, a great and prosperous\nsociety grew in the lands of the west. \nAs time wore on, many eastern \npilgrims settled in the lands \nsurrounding Khanduras and soon \nestablish small, self contained \nkingdoms. A few of these kingdoms \nbickered with Khanduras over \nholdings of property or routes of trade. \nThese squabbles did little to upset the \nlasting peace of the west, and the \ngreat northern kingdom of Westmarch \nproved to be a strong ally of \nKhanduras as the two lands steadily \nengaged in ventures of barter and \ncommerce.\n\nDuring this time, a bold, new religion \nof the light known as Zakarum began\nto spread throughout the kingdom of \nWestmarch and into many of its\nnorthern principalities. Zakarum, \nfounded in the far east, implored \nfollowers to enter into the light and \nforsake the darkness that lurked \nwithin their souls. The people of \nWestmarch adopted the statues of \nZakarum as their sacred mission in \nthe world. Westmarch began to turn \ntowards its neighbors, expecting them \nto embrace this "new beginning" as \nwell. Tensions rose between the \nkingdoms of Westmarch and \nKhanduras as the priests of Zakarum\nbegan to preach their foreign dogma \nwhether they were welcomed or not.\n\nIt was then that the great northern \nlord Leoric came unto the lands of \nKhanduras and, in the name of \nZakarum, declared himself king. \nLeoric was a deeply religious man \nand had brought many knights and \npriests with him that comprised his \nOrder of the Light. Leoric and his \ntrusted advisor, the Arch Bishop \nLazarus, made their way to the city of \nTristram. Leoric appropriated the \nancient, decrepit monastery on the \noutskirts of the town for his seat of \npower and renovated it to match its \ntime-lost glory. Although the free \npeople of Khanduras were not \npleased with being placed under the \nsudden rule of a foreign king, Leoric \nserved them with justice and might. \nEventually, the people of Khanduras \ngrew to respect the kind Leoric, \nsensing that he sought only to guide \nand protect them against the \noppression of darkness.\n
awakening	30\nThe Awakening\n\nNot long after Leoric took possession \nof Khanduras, a power long asleep \nawakened within the dark recesses \nbeneath the Monastery. Sensing that \nfreedom was within his grasp, Diablo \nentered the nightmares of the \narch-bishop and lured him into the \ndark, subterranean labyrinth. In his\nterror, Lazarus raced throughout the \nabandoned hallways until he at last\ncame to the chamber of the burning \nsoulstone. No longer in command of \nhis body or spirit, he raised the stone \nabove his head and uttered words \nlong forgotten in the realms of mortals. \nHis will destroyed, Lazarus shattered\nthe soulstone upon the ground. \nDiablo once again came into the \nworld of man. Although he was \nreleased from his imprisonment within \nthe soulstone, the Lord of Terror was \nstill greatly weakened from his long \nsleep and required an anchor to the \nworld. Once he had found a mortal \nform to wear, he could begin to \nreclaim his vastly depleted power. \nThe great demon weighed the souls \nresiding in the town above, and \nchose to take the strongest of them -\nthat of King Leoric.\n\nFor many months King Leoric secretly \nfought the evil presence that twisted \nhis thoughts and emotions. Sensing \nthat he had been possessed by some \nunknown evil, Leoric  hid his dark \nsecret from his priests, hoping that \nsomehow his own devout \nrighteousness would be enough to \nexorcise that corruption growing \ninside him - he was sorely mistaken. \nDiablo stripped away the core of \nLeoric's being, burning away all \nhonor and virtue from his soul. \nLazarus too, had fallen under the \nsway of the demon, keeping close to \nLeoric at all times. Lazarus worked to \nconceal the plans of his new master \nfrom the Order of Light, hoping that \nthe demon's power would grow, well \nconcealed amongst the servants of \nZakarum.\n\nThe priests of Zakarum and the \ncitizenry of Khanduras recognized the \ndisturbing change within their liege. \nHis once proud and rugged form\nbecame distorted and deformed. King \nLeoric became increasingly deranged\nand ordered immediate executions of \nany who dared to question his \nmethods or authority. Leoric began to \nsend his knights to other villages to \nbully their townspeople into \nsubmission. The people of Khanduras \nwho had once grown to see great \nhonor in their ruler began to call \nLeoric the Black King.\n
darkeningoftristram	30\nThe Darkening of Tristram\n\nThe absence of prying advisors and \ninquisitive priests left Diablo free to \nassume total control over the king's \nbattered soul. As the Lord of Terror \nattempted to strengthen his hold upon \nthe maddened king, he found that \nthe lingering spirit of Leoric fought \nwith him still. Although the control \nover Leoric that Diablo held was \nformidable, the demon knew that in \nhis weakened state he could never \ntake complete possession of his soul \nas long as a glimmer of his will \nremained. The demonlord sought a \nfresh and innocent host upon which \nto build his terror. \n\nThe demon relinquished his control \nover Leoric, but the king's soul was \nleft corrupted and his mind crazed. \nDiablo began to search throughout \nKhanduras for the perfect vessel to \nact as his focus, and found such a \nsoul easily within his reach. Enjoined \nby his dark master, Lazarus \nkidnapped Albrecht - the only son of \nLeoric - and dragged the terrified\nyouth down into the blackness of the \nlabyrinth. Flooding the boy's \ndefenseless mind with the essence \nof pure terror, Diablo easily took \npossession of the young Albrecht.\n\nPain and fire raced through the child's \nsoul. Hideous laughter filled his head \nand clouded his thoughts. Paralyzed \nwith fear, Albrecht felt the presence \nof Diablo within his mind as it seemed \nto push him down, deeper and deeper \ninto darkness and oblivion. Diablo \ngazed upon his surroundings through \nthe eyes of the young prince. A \nlustful hunger still tortured the demon \nafter his frustrating bout for control \nover Leoric, but the nightmares of the \nboy provided ample substance to \nsate him. Reaching deep into \nAlbrecht's subconscious, Diablo \nripped the greatest fears of the child \nfrom their hiding places and gave \nthem breath.\n
reignofdiablo	30\nThe Reign of Diablo\n\nThe Black King lay dead, slain at the \nhands of his own priests and knights. \nThe young Prince Albrecht was still \nmissing, and the proud defenders of \nKhanduras were no more. The people \nof Tristram looked about their lifeless \ntown and were greatly dismayed. \nAwash in feelings of both relief and \nremorse, they soon realized that their \ntroubles had merely begun. Strange, \neerie lights appeared in the darkened \nwindows of the monastery. \nMisshapen, leathery-skinned \ncreatures were seen venturing forth \nfrom the shadows of the church. \nHorrible, wounded cries seemed to \nlinger in the wind, emanating from \ndeep underground. It became \napparent that something quite \nunnatural had infested the once holy \nsight...\n\nTravelers on the roads surrounding \nTristram were accosted by cloaked\nriders that seemed to now constantly \nroam the deserted countryside. Many\nvillagers fled Tristram, making their \nway to other towns or kingdoms, \nfearing some unnamed evil that \nseemed to wait in the shadows all \naround them. Those few chose to \nremain seldom ventured out at night, \nand never tread foot upon the \ngrounds of the cursed monastery. \nWhispered rumors of poor, innocent \npeople being abducted in the night by \nwicked, nightmarish creatures filled \nthe halls of the local inn. With no king, \nno law, and no army left to defend \nthem, many of the townsfolk began to \nfear an attack from the things that \nnow dwelt beneath their town.\n\nThe arch-bishop Lazarus, frayed and \ndisheveled, returned from his \nabsence and assured the townsfolk \nthat he too had been ravaged by\nthe growing evil of the monastery. \nWith their desperate need for \nreassurance clouding their good \njudgement, Lazarus whipped the \ntownspeople into a frenzied mob. \nReminding them that Prince Albrecht \nwas still unaccounted for, he \npersuaded many of the men to follow \nhim into the depths of the monastery \nto search for the boy. They gathered \ntorches and soon the night air glowed \nwith the flickering light of hope. They \narmed themselves with shovels, picks \nand scythes and so prepared, they \nboldly followed the treacherous\narch-bishop straight into the fiery \nmaw of hell itself...\n\nThe few who survived the horrible \nfate that awaited them returned to \nTristram and recounted what they \ncould of the ordeal. Their wounds\nwere terrible, and even the skills of \nthe healer could not save some of\nthem. As the stories of demons and \ndevils spread, a stifling, primal terror\nbegan to consume the hearts of all \nthe town's inhabitants. It was a terror\nthat none of them had ever known...\n\nDeep beneath the foundations of the \nruined monastery, Diablo gorged\nhimself upon the fears of the mortals \nabove him. He slowly sank back into\nthe welcoming shadows and began \nto harness his depleted power.\n\nHe smiled to himself in the sheltering \ndarkness, for he knew that the time \nof his final victory was fast \napproaching...\n
wagesofthesinwar	45\nThe Wages of the Sin War\n\nTake heed and bear witness to the \ntruths that lie herein, for they are the last \nlegacy of the Horadrim. When the \nEternal Conflict between the High \nHeavens and the Burning Hells falls \nupon mortal soil, it is called the Sin War. \nAngels and Demons walk amongst \nhumanity in disguise, fighting in secret, \naway from the prying eyes of mortals. \nSome daring, powerful mortals have \neven allied themselves with either side, \nand helped to dictate the course of the \nSin War. \n
taleofthehoradrim	45\nThe Tale of the Horadrim\n\nTake heed and bear witness to the \ntruths that lie herein, for they are the \nlast legacy of the Horadrim. Nearly \nthree hundred years ago, it came to \nbe known that the Three Prime Evils \nof the Burning Hells had mysteriously\ncome to our world. The Three \nBrothers ravaged the lands of the \neast for decades, while humanity was \nleft trembling in their wake. Our Order -\nthe Horadrim - was founded by a \ngroup of secretive magi to hunt down \nand capture the Three Evils once \nand for all.\n\nThe original Horadrim captured two of \nthe Three within powerful artifacts \nknown as Soulstones and buried \nthem deep beneath the desolate\neastern sands. The third Evil escaped \ncapture and fled to the west with \nmany of the Horadrim in pursuit. The \nThird Evil - known as Diablo, the\nLord of Terror - was eventually \ncaptured, his essence set in a \nSoulstone and buried within this \nLabyrinth.\n\nBe warned that the soulstone must \nbe kept from discovery by those not \nof the faith. If Diablo were to be \nreleased, he would seek a body that\nis easily controlled as he would be \nvery weak - perhaps that of an old \nman or a child. \n
darkexile2	45\nThe Dark Exile\n\nSo it came to be that there was a great \nrevolution within the Burning Hells known \nas The Dark Exile. The Lesser Evils \noverthrew the Three Prime Evils and \nbanished their spirit forms to the mortal \nrealm. The demons Belial (the Lord of \nLies) and Azmodan (the Lord of Sin) \nfought to claim rulership of Hell during the \nabsence of the Three Brothers. All of \nHell polarized between the factions of \nBelial and Azmodan while the forces of \nthe High Heavens continually battered \nupon the very Gates of Hell. \n
sinwar2	45\nThe Sin War\n\nMany demons traveled to the mortal \nrealm in search of the Three Brothers. \nThese demons were followed to the \nmortal plane by Angels who hunted them \nthroughout the vast cities of the East. \nThe Angels allied themselves with a \nsecretive Order of mortal magi named the \nHoradrim, who quickly became adept at \nhunting demons. They also made many \ndark enemies in the underworlds. \n
horazon2	45\nIt seems that I may have brought \nsomething to this plane that even I cannot \ncontrol. The creature that fell into my \nastral trap is a very deadly demon. I have \nbeen able to bind it at the bottom of a pit, \nbut it kills everything that I have sent there \nin attempts to defeat it. While it cannot \nescape, it does block the tunnels that lead \nto my protected haven. I am tempted to \nuse the switch to open the tunnels to see \nif it will just leave, but I fear it is smarter \nthan most of the lesser demons I have \ntrapped before. If I could just lure it \nsomewhere else...\n
horazon1	45\nLet this tome serve as your warning. \nThis is a forbidden place. Return from \nwhence you came and your life will be \nspared. Horazon, master of the \ndisciplines that summon and bind \ncreatures to this plane, promises death \nto those who pass beyond the five pillars. \nYou have been admonished.\n
bingingofthe32	45\nThe Binding of the Three\n\nSo it came to be that the Three Prime \nEvils were banished in spirit form to the \nmortal realm and after sowing chaos \nacross the East for decades, they were \nhunted down by the cursed Order of the \nmortal Horadrim. The Horadrim used \nartifacts called Soulstones to contain the \nessence of Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred \nand his brother Baal, the Lord of \nDestruction. The youngest brother - \nDiablo, the Lord of Terror - escaped \nto the west.\n\nEventually the Horadrim captured \nDiablo within a Soulstone as well,\nand buried him under an ancient, \nforgotten Cathedral. There, the Lord of\nTerror sleeps and awaits the time of \nhis rebirth. Know ye that he will seek\na body of youth and power to possess \n- one that is innocent and easily \ncontrolled. He will then arise to free his \nBrothers and once more fan the flames\nof the Sin War... \n
realmsbeyond	45\nThe Realms Beyond\n\nAll praises to Diablo - Lord of Terror and \nSurvivor of The Dark Exile. When he \nawakened from his long slumber, my \nLord and Master spoke to me of secrets \nthat few mortals know. He told me the \nkingdoms of the High Heavens and the \npits of the Burning Hells engage in an \neternal war. He revealed the powers that \nhave brought this discord to the realms \nof man. My lord has named the battle for \nthis world and all who exist here the Sin \nWar. \n
taleofthe3	45\nTale of the Three\n\nGlory and Approbation to Diablo - Lord of \nTerror and Leader of the Three. My Lord \nspoke to me of his two Brothers, \nMephisto and Baal, who were banished \nto this world long ago. My Lord wishes to \nbide his time and harness his awesome \npower so that he may free his captive \nbrothers from their tombs beneath the \nsands of the east. Once my Lord releases \nhis Brothers, the Sin War will once again \nknow the fury of the Three. \n
blackking1	45\nThe Black King\n\nHail and Sacrifice to Diablo - Lord of \nTerror and Destroyer of Souls. When I \nawoke my Master from his sleep, he \nattempted to possess a mortal's form. \nDiablo attempted to claim the body of \nKing Leoric, but my Master was too weak \nfrom his imprisonment. My Lord required \na simple and innocent anchor to this \nworld, and so found the boy Albrecht to \nbe perfect for the task. While the good \nKing Leoric was left maddened by \nDiablo's unsuccessful possession, I \nkidnapped his son Albrecht and brought \nhim before my Master. I now await \nDiablo's call and pray that I will be \nrewarded when he at last emerges as the \nLord of this world.\n
nakrul	45\nI have tried spells, threats, abjuration, \nand bargaining with this foul creature - to \nno avail. My methods of enslaving lesser \ndemons seem to have no effect on this \nfearsome beast...\n\nIn its ranting, the creature has let slip its \nname - Na-krul. I have attempted to \nresearch the name, but the smaller \ndemons have somehow destroyed my \nlibrary. Na-krul...the name fills me with a \ncold dread. I prefer to think of it only as a \ncreature, rather than ponder its true \nname...\n\nMy time is quickly running out. I must \nrecord the ways to contain the demon, \nand then conceal that text, lest his \nminions find some way to use my \nknowledge and free their lord. I hope \nthat whoever finds this journal will \nseek the knowledge.\n
chamberofbone	60\nBeyond the hall of heroes lies the \nchamber of bone. Eternal death awaits \nany who would seek to steal the \ntreasures secured within this room. So \nspeaks the Lord of Terror, and so it is \nwritten.\n
hallsofblind	60\nI can see what you see not.\nVision milky then eyes rot.\nWhen you turn they will be gone,\nwhispering their hidden song.\nThen you see what cannot be,\nshadows move where light should be.\nOut of darkness, out of mind,\ncast down into the Halls of the Blind.\n
